The fact that
everything that was done with intention
and the way the whole process and I'm
just talking about everything from
after the season to now like how
everything that when you plan it you
start to see it come together. Listen,
we're we're still a long ways away. But
the process of what um
what I wanted what me and Mosh wanted to
do um coaching staff, players
um like that whole process like you
could just you could see it and I guess
that's why I'm outstanding. How much
closer are you to where you want to be
where your vision was where you were
hired?
Listen, we're still a long ways away. I
mean obviously when you when you finish
the season 3 and 14
um and you going into this year and you
feel good about some of the things that
you that you that you've done uh you
want to see how you know all those
things come together, you know from
like OTAs and training camp then going
to the season. So that's a hard question
to to answer really, you know, but I do
know this
um everything that that we want to do as
an organization you starting to see it,
you know, start to come together. And
again we still have a long ways to way a
long ways to go, but I do like the
direction that we're going right now. So
G
Say it again. Why G though? um
It's something about
a quarterback and I'm I'm I'm going to
say a quarterback with a chip on the
shoulder.
um
And listen, he he's proven a lot in this
league of what he's done. I'm especially
when you take those time when he was in
Seattle. um
Listen, he fits exactly what we're
trying to do. So obviously we've created
an identity. The foundation of our
offense is is pretty good now. When it
when you look at the offensive line, I
mean obviously we ended up signing Pooh
Bear to be our left guard. um You look
at our backs that we have. You look at
the tight ends that we have. um The
receiver room, I like our receiver room
um and Garrett's coming back. You know,
I think he's the perfect guy to fit
exactly what we want to do especially
when we can run the ball the way that we
can run it and now be able to add some
play action. um I think he's perfect for
that. How much with Geno um considering
he had some struggles last year
obviously, how much consideration was
given to maybe bringing in competition
for him? um You always want to bring in
competition. um And that's going to
happen organically. You know what I'm
saying? But like I just feel like like
he's the guy that's going to lead us to
the promised land. He's the guy that's
going to touch the ball more than
anybody else on offense. And listen, I
know he had his struggles and I think a
lot of quarterbacks, you know, they have
their struggles. If you look at uh over
the last 5 years the guy has that's
thrown the most interception, I mean the
top guys are up there. You know, so um
but I do know this
he understand exactly what happened last
year. You know, I don't want to get too
far into that cuz I wasn't there
obviously with the Raiders, but I do
know that man he um
there's some things that he knows he can
correct. And he had he's at fault on
some of those, you know, but there's
some things that he knows that he's
going to get better at and um and I look
forward to him doing that.
>> Obviously obviously you added a lot of
veterans especially on the defense like
Demario Davis. How can that help you
especially with all the changes that you
have coming this year? I I think you
guys really um
can really see exactly what we were
trying to do when it came to that. I
think we're the second youngest team in
the league last year and to be able to
have an influx of these veteran guys to
be able to teach these guys exactly how
does the locker room need to operate? um
How do you finish out games? And I'm
saying that is because guys like Demario
who I've been with, guys like David
Onyemata who I've been with, guys like
Minkah that is man, we already know what
he can do in this league. When you start
to add guys like that, man, I think it
only helps what you're trying to create
when it comes to a team. So all those
guys that we added in free agency brings
a certain level of um
of um
adult you know, to our team that we
need. So um I'm excited about that. So
it's it's kind of a bigger picture
question, but yep. reflecting on your
time in Detroit a little bit. So you
look at the situation there with Dan
Campbell to lose so many different
people. Now you're in a position where
you're head coach navigating change. I'm
talking you you haven't got to that
position where the team has been good at
all like that, but just how was it to
navigate change and then still try to
continue to be a contender at the same
time? Like How do you and do you feel do
you feel like Detroit is still a
contender? Okay, I want to make sure I
understand the question when you you're
saying that they lost so many Yeah, like
when you lose like seven eight coaches
staff members Oh, when you man just come
and still kind of trying to navigate
being a contender. How difficult now
that you're being a head coach do you
think that is to still work to be a
contender? No, I understand. I
understand and and it's um
it's a really good problem to have
because usually when you're losing
coaches like that that means you're
doing well. You know, so but you all you
have to have a vision of what you want
within your coaching staff. And once you
start to once you see that and
understand that and then you start to
seek out like guys that can replace
those guys that um that left. But the
thing that I think the most important
thing is now you have a true vision of
what you want to to bring in your staff
to make sure everybody clicks. And
listen, I know Dan's going to do a hell
of a job doing that. um But again it's a
nice problem to have when you're losing
coaches that tells you that you're
winning games. So what do you You you
guys a year ago you were talking us
about Justin Fields the guy obviously
invested a lot of money in him. Like how
how do you reflect back on that
experience and how much you can learn
from that as a coach in terms of like
how you approach That was a situation
that it just didn't work out, you know,
um
I can't sit here and say listen, I
regret you know, because I think
Justin's a really good player. And
I and I said I put the fault on me. I
didn't do enough to put him in a
position to to to be successful. And I'm
always going to say that, you know,
that's my job as the head coach. So um I
think he's going to do well in Kansas, I
really do cuz he's a good person for one
and he's a good player. um I think
Andrew Reid's going to do a good job
with him. You know, and there were some
things that I've learned of making sure
man, how do I identify with every player
can do and make sure they do a good job.
There's been a lot of chatter about
incorporating three four elements since
Could you just from
sake of clarity could you what's the
defense going to be?
>> [laughter]
>> And you do hear that a lot. um
And I'm going to say this we we are a we
will be a multiple defense. So there
will be
elements of 4-3, there'll be elements of
3-4. And I think sometimes that's
overblown. When you look at it you're in
nickel like 70% of the time. So you're
in a four down spacing for the most
part. So once you go to base defense,
man, there's a number of things that you
can do. I I love front variations. So
you will see some four down fronts, you
will see some five down fronts and you
will see a lot of movement within that.
So I don't want to sit here and say
exactly who we're going to be because
we're going to be a little bit of
everything to be honest with you. But
it'll be easy for our players to be able
to go out there and and compete. Hey G,
after after your your self-reflection
Yeah.
what can you give us an an idea of what
you want to do differently in year two
and you kind of stay true to yourself
about what you want to Yeah and and
to answer that like all self-reflection
was not on the negative part to be
honest with you. It's just looking at
some things that like for practice for
example, like there's some things I want
to do different when it comes to
practice. I want to be able to maximize
our reps as much as I can and also make
sure there's recovery for the players.
um There's certain ways that I want to
go about game management, you know, with
Burton. There's certain things that that
we want to push forward especially now
since I'm I'm calling the defense.
>> Yeah. um And then there's some things
like offensively that I want to make
sure we take advantage of and that's one
of the reasons why uh Frank was was high
on the list, you know, to be able to
understand exactly how is he's going to
create these matchups that we want to
create. um And there's things about
messaging with the players that I I I I
want to improve on to make sure there's
clarity on what we're trying to do and
how we're trying to do it. So there's a
number of things and those is a couple
examples that um
that I sit back and I look at and I
think every year you want to improve on
those things. Just to piggyback off of
that Ashley asked Dan Campbell about you
and he said the biggest advice he give
to you is just to trust your process.
Yeah. Obviously you made a lot of
coaching changes. So how do you manage
that trusting your process but knowing
you needed to make those changes?
>> That's that's that's a really good
question and and that's something that
um
that's something like it's that will be
a foundation of how we operate is
everything that we do and this is
another evaluation part. Everything that
we do like there will be a process
behind it. And when I say that to me a
process you have a vision that you see.
This vision is this way. All right? And
if you're trusting your process, man,
you're like you're detailed on every
little step before you get there cuz you
can't get to that vision without being
detailed not missing these steps. And I
want to make sure that everything that
we do we do that. Now that might the
timing of it might be different for some
people and [clears throat] that's just
what it is, you know, cuz I don't want
to miss any steps. Now um I don't want
to make any mistakes when it comes to
that. Obviously mistakes can happen, but
I don't want to sit here and make
mistakes because I didn't go through
that process. So everything that we do
will be process oriented. Circling back
to to Geno Aaron is
uh you can probably say this about a lot
of quarterbacks, but he seems like a
very different player. He's protected.
He has a clean pocket. And again I know
every quarterback but like he really is
a different guy when he's able to
>> You're right.
You're right. um You guys have built a
pretty decent line. And so was that also
a factor involved that you think
[clears throat] you can keep him upright
which will be able to maximize what he
does?
>> glad you said that cuz you're absolutely
right when it comes to um
Geno being successful is like
how do you protect the quarterbacks you
allow him to be do that. And we as we do
have a good line. We do and we're steady
um bringing guys in that could help in
that aspect unless somebody goes down.
So um Listen, I look forward to seeing
him operate behind that line. I I really
do cuz I think he's going to create some
damage because of the arm talent. um
And man, he's grown so much as far as
his smarts, as far as IDs, as far as
protection and things like that. And I
knew that playing against him, you know,
when he was in Seattle because you watch
him and you see the man he's controlling
everything. And that was the one thing
that really stuck out and I played like
Yeah, I thought they were in our
division when we talked we played them
them every year. Um but to see how he
operates, man, it was um
man, it was good to see. It was.
>> Is there something to be said about a
guy like him who's unafraid to make
mistakes, too, like that?
>> again.
A guy who's unafraid to make mistakes.
He's going to take shots down the field
even if there's a chance he might get
picked off. Like I know you want the
balance of
>> Yeah. Yeah. Now Now and I I said this
last year
with Justin is this is going to be
aggressive, we don't want to be
reckless.
Now, I think the one thing that Geno
does a really good job he gives his guys
an opportunity. And sometimes you got
guys like Garrett, he could be covered
but he's not covered.
You know, because of the way he could
contort his body and go up and catch the
ball. So Um I think he understands that
very well. I think he's going to allow
our guys to be able to do that. You
know, him, AD, Mason, all those guys.
Man, those guys can be covered but man,
let's put the ball where, you know, the
defender can't defend it. I think he can
do a good job with that. You you were
talking about the you talked about how
he's been having a chip on his shoulder,
right? That's something people have said
about you in the past. So
does does chip recognize chip?
>> [laughter]
>> Um
I think there's a synergy that draws us
together. You know, when you have
something like that and there's nothing
um there's nothing better in this league
than having players um that has an edge.
And I don't want to sit here and say
that because they're trying to prove
something, it's more or less they're
trying to prove themselves right of who
they think they are or who we think we
are.
And
man, it's just a mentality.
And this league is really about mindset
for the most part. And we can get that
mindset with everybody on this team, uh
there's good things to come. When you're
having When you're having internal
discussions on whether to bring Geno in,
how much does the his history with the
Jets
was turbulent, it was rocky. The fans
have long memories, they remember he had
some rough moments.
>> Yeah. Those things Listen, those things
are all you always weigh. And
to me at the end of the day, I didn't
think they would be a detriment, you
know, to us as an organization, to the
fans. Um obviously there's some fans
that that that probably didn't like it
and I understand, but I know there's
some fans that did like it, you know, so
um Listen, he has a fresh start. You
know, and and
I look forward to what he's going to
operate. I do because he he he really
really wants this. And just going
through the process of of getting the
quarterback, that was something that
stood out to about him. Like he he wants
to be here. And when you have guys that
really want to be here, want to be Jets,
that only makes it better. With Geno, I
I think a lot of people in the public
the thought is you look at him to stop
gap. It's it's one year then you guys
get your quarterback 2027, but do you
view this as as the potential for a
multi-year partnership as we've seen
around the league with quarterbacks
aren't Yeah.
>> they're they're playing much longer into
their careers now. Well, I don't think
that's a um
that's a question to really for me to
really answer because listen, he can go
out there and throw for 4,000 yards and
have 30 touchdowns and no interceptions
and
>> [laughter]
>> and we're you think we're just going to
let him go, you know?
So I think that just goes by year. And
listen, he's um
I do know this.
He's excited about being here. And
listen, he's going to be our quarterback
and I look forward to that. I mean,
obviously you continue to to try to
build your organization or your team
with with good players and we're going
to continue to do that.
>> Since Connor brought it up,
there's a lot of chatter and narrative
now to the Jets try to get their
quarterback for the future this in this
year's draft with like a Ty Simpson or
do you wait till next year when there's
supposedly a bunch of them? Yeah.
>> coach, yeah,
you know, how do you how do you balance
that? What's your feeling on that whole
thing? My feeling is man, you always
want to get you always want to build
your roster with good players and
whatever position that is. I mean,
obviously quarterback is a is a top
position on your team. And if we feel
like he's the best player on the board,
then that's what we do, that's what we
draft. The thing is we're not trying to
reach and grab for guys, we're trying to
just draft guys cuz uh
like the best player available. Yeah.
Obviously we saw you and Woody like
doing the pro day tours as well. When
you were a scout, what was some of the
things first things you looked at when
you were evaluating players and like how
can that help you in throughout this
process? Let me talk about exactly like
that that whole like trip that we had
that week long trip. Now that was
something that we did in New Orleans for
man, my six years there and I thought it
was outstanding. And the reason why is
you really get a chance to sit with the
player and really get a chance to
understand the character of the player.
Man, obviously you're not going to get
everything, but to be able to go to
dinner with those guys, be able to sit
and put them through classwork, man, you
really get a chance to know the player
really really well. So I really love
that process. Um
and that's something I I know for a fact
that we continue to do, you know, so
going through this whole process and
really get trying to get a chance to
know the players, man, it is it's
critical cuz you want to know exactly
who you're bringing in that locker room.
Cuz that's a sacred place and most
players would tell you that, especially
the veteran players.
Um and I want to make sure I do right by
them. Every player that we bring on this
team, I want to make sure they fit
exactly what we're trying to do.
>> How do you balance that like what they
produced on the field versus also the
character of the
>> Say it again.
You balance like the character of the
player and also what you see on film.
>> Well, obviously you want guys that are
going to produce. I mean, that's that's
that's part of the business. And to me,
I think the easiest thing to to look at
or look for is talent. You know, the
hardest thing is who the player really
is. I'm a firm believer that your
character is going to show up on the
field at some point, you know, so you
want to make sure you try to identify
that as much as possible. The talent, I
mean, it is what it is. You're a 4-3
guy, you're a 4-5, man, you're 6-5, 250,
like all that stuff is easy. It's in the
production part is easy, too. You know,
now is can the player be coachable
enough to improve on what he's doing? A
lot of that has to do with your football
character. When you sat down there when
you sat down to formulate your plan
defensively, obviously you wanted
leadership that's there with Demario
Davis
and Jordan Whitehead. How much also are
you thinking we need guys that are going
to take the ball away after what you've
been doing last year because obviously
Minkah's done that a lot in his career.
Right had a great season last year.
Well, listen, I I I've
just like you guys saw it, I saw it,
too. And it doesn't feel good, you know,
but I mean, obviously you see that um
you got a guy like Minkah, you got a guy
like Demario that can affect the passing
and and affect the of the ball. We
brought in Naquan, you know, a guy that
led the league in picks. I mean, that
was obviously something that we had to
get better at. And the only way you can
get better at things like that is go out
get guys that can do it, you know, so
those guys have done it at a high level.
Um so I'll look forward to them doing it
again. With Aaron, what's um what's it
like for you going into year two but
having an entirely new coaching staff?
Um
and I answered that question earlier and
listen, it's part of the business. And
the coaches that I wanted to it was
intentional. And obviously when I let go
Steve Wilks during the season, man,
there was going to be an opportunity for
me to actually like re-evaluate what we
want to do on the defense, how we want
to do it, the right guys that would
uh end up fitting what we're trying to
do. And that's what we did. And knowing
that I was going to be the play caller,
I wanted to make sure that I brought
somebody as a coordinator that knows
exactly what I'm trying to do. You know,
and I want those guys to be a part of,
too, him and Frank, you know, Duce and
Frank to be a part of building this. But
I want to make sure there was synergy
between myself and every coach that was
on that that we have. We want to ask
you, sorry, and then I'm out of here.
Pierre Desir. Yeah. I I don't know he
didn't play much for you last year. Did
you get to know him much and what do you
make of him in your division?
>> outstanding player. Obviously I thought
he was having an outstanding camp. Um
actually as we went through our grades,
man, he was actually graded now in each
practice as the highest player on the
O-line was and you hate to see it for a
player of his caliber cuz he's such a
good player and it seems like something
just happens every year, you know, with
him. So hopefully he will um he'll go
out there. Listen, I'm rooting for him.
I really am cuz he's a damn good player.
What has it been like having Frank in
the building besides having somebody
Yeah.
>> You know, you obviously know him a long
time, but you know, he comes in with so
much experience he's built the offense
out in in the NFL. It It's It's been
outstanding. Um obviously it's just you
guys understand exactly how the process
has been going overall is man, I'm
installing with the defense and like
man, we're like we're moving. You know,
and the good thing is is Duce knows the
defense very well. So that process has
been going outstanding. And then I can
step out and let Duce continue to
install with the coaches and then I'm in
there with the offense and just listen
to listen to how Frank wants to do
things and the input that he's getting,
you know, from the other guys has been
outstanding. Um and we have some really
like innovative young guys that's on
that offensive staff that's that's
like I can see these guys being like
coordinators and possible head coach.
I'll tell you what, Seth Ryan,
just just keep your eye on him. Just
telling you that right now. He's going
to be a hell of a coach. And the ideas
that he bring and here's another thing.
So here
like we're talking about AI quite a bit
in our meetings. And these young guys,
like we got two young guys, Merkle
from Stanford. And these guys are like
on top of that. And it's those guys are
teaching us how to utilize like all of
that stuff. It's been outstanding. So
man, we're trying to take that next
step, you know, us as coaches.
>> you guys utilizing AI? Man, just
what we information putting in and just
like I'm still trying to [laughter]
figure it out,
you You but but I will say this, yeah,
we all are.
But, um, man, it's it's it's been good.
I would tell you that. And sometimes
it's shocking to see like the
information. Now,
it's not the only thing that you do, but
to be able to see the information that
you can get has been, um,
>> You're not putting in like what place
you're calling from? No.
>> [laughter]
>> No, no, I'm I'm I'm trusting myself on
that.
You know, but just inputting information
into the system and being able to move
efficiently and faster has been really
good for us. AG, at this time of year,
there's a lot of discussion with the
draft of positional value. You can't
pick a running back here. You can't pick
a safety here, right? Yeah. 2023 with
the Lions. I know what you're going to
ask. You guys take Gibbs and you take
Campbell. Yeah. And and it's like, oh my
god, F grade the next day. You guys got
hammered on that and that's really
worked out very well in Detroit.
>> And they're two all-pros. Right. Did you
I imagine you had opinions before that,
but did that teach you anything that
experience of going through that draft
and and what's where's your feeling on
that? Yeah, this has been this is, um,
I've learned this really with Sean
Payton.
Um,
man, you got to shut the outside noise.
And who do you love?
If you love the player, go get the
player.
And like I truly believe in that. If you
love the player, go get it regardless of
what everybody's saying, regardless of
positional value. If you love the
player, go and get him. And obviously,
we don't we and D'Onta were together in
New Orleans all those years. And that
that never left us. And um,
I'm not changing that either. And that's
something that, um, me and Mosi talked
about a lot. And and we utilize that. If
we love the player, man, we going to get
him. So, Caleb Downs at two, then,
right?
>> [laughter]
>> If we love the player,
we going to get him. We still we still
in the process of evaluating all this
stuff.
That's okay. But, no, but like put if
you could put your old scout's hat on
for a second. Like when you have a guy
like Ar'mani Woods,
didn't have the much on paper, did not
have crazy numbers, but yet everyone
says he's just such an
athletic freak and has all the
measurables and that sort of like as a
scout slash coach, how do you
Well,
>> look at something like I think the you
hit it on the head. The first thing is,
man, the traits.
Um, arm length, weight, um, speed, um,
ankle flexion, like all those things
that you're trying to look at. And then,
like,
the coach that can actually coach him to
get to that next level.
And then, does he have the football
character to allow himself to be able to
be coached, to be able to do those
things? Like all those things
like has to be evaluated when you're
looking at a guy like that. Um, listen,
who was it?
I think it was Danielle Hunter.
I think it was Danielle Hunter. He I
like his stats wasn't up there, but he
had all the traits.
And then, you had a coach that can coach
him to be where he's at right now. So, I
look at it the same way.
Um,
man, it's it's a combination of the
traits and it's a combination of the
football character. Again,
is that player coachable enough to be
able to do the things that you want him
to do to be successful?
AG, Jamaal
obviously how you guys tagged him. He's
going to go through the business and the
football here for a little while. Did
you have any Did you have any
conversations with him after the tagging
cuz
I'm not sure he's going to come to
the spring cuz a lot of times guys who
get tagged don't show up. Did you talk
to him at all about how to navigate this
this situation?
>> we talked about it beforehand. And
listen,
and you guys know, man, I'm a huge fan
of Jamaal Charles. I think Jamaal
Charles is is is a top running back in
this league. Um, and I would say this,
you know, once we get through with the
draft, I'm sure that's going to be
revisited. I think Mosi already said
that.
We'll see exactly how they go. And I
Jamaal Charles knows where I stand. And
he doesn't need a lecture from me on on
how this goes. Um, man, we talked with
actually we talked before, um,
before he got tagged. And he knows
exactly, you know, where he stands with
the team. And when you go to these when
you go to these pro days and you look at
quarterbacks in particular, Yeah. do you
find yourself looking at them as a
defender or as a defensive mind saying,
how how am I going to stop this guy? Or
do you see him as what kind of what can
an offense do with him? Like that that's
a good question because I do. I look at
it from from like different angles. And
one, if I'm a if I'm a defensive player,
like how would I defend him? What are
the issues that we feel like he'll have?
And then we try to put them through
drills. So, for example, um,
we have one of our coaches, you know,
when he drop when one of the
quarterbacks drop back, man, I want to
attack him and see how he like how he
can maneuver in the pocket to be able to
get himself free to be able to deliver
the ball. So, those are things that
defensively I want to see him do that.
Offensively, just all the little small
details of the drop, um, three-step,
five-step, uh, under center, play
action, ball handling, like all those
things that you want to look at as an
offensive coach and now you see if he
fits what we're trying to do. So, you're
right, I look at it from both angles.
What did you guys like about O Sai and
Kingsley? Or how do you envision those
guys fitting in? Okay. Kingsley,
um,
6'5", 270.
When you look at the defenses I've been
on from New Orleans to Detroit to now,
man, he fits exactly and I call him a
rush, which he's really defensive end.
Um,
from Cam Jordan,
um,
to Hutch, like he fits that mold of that
type. Now, totally different players,
but as far as what we're trying to to to
build to make sure that we have a guy on
the edge that can really set it. And
they be able to rush with power. All
right, so he was one of outside, he can
do a lot of different things. He can
play the rush, he can play the Sam. Um,
he can drop into coverage. Uh, he's
played special teams quite a bit. Um,
he's disruptive. I mean, he had like
five or six sacks, you know, like I
think the last So, we can utilize him in
a number of different spots. I think
that's the best thing about where we're
at right now. So, we have a number of
guys that we can maneuver and move
around to be able to do some things. I
mean, Will right now, I mean, I
I can't wait to see what the things that
we're going to do. Where you guys can't
wait to see what we're going to do with
Will. Um, so it's exciting right now to
have those guys. And we have like that
many weapons on defense to be able to do
some things. AG, what what's it been
like to see the way Mosi operates? Like
I
he's I mean, you guys obviously work
together. I know he's made a lot of
trades where he, you know, in between
the margins that trading and what with
these young players. I'm just curious
what it's been like working with him.
You know what? I I think the
the best thing in
you hear this quite a bit on head coach
and GM relationship is the way that we
communicate.
And it's, um,
like we really communicate at a high
level. And it's on every little thing
that we do. And that's the type of
relationship I wanted with a GM to where
when it comes to things in in his
department, like he would ask me
questions, how do I feel? When it comes
to things in the coaching department,
like I'm going to ask him questions, how
does he feel? Now, I think you you you
want to do that cuz I think it brings
you closer, you know, as as as cuz we're
in this thing together. And listen,
we're we're in lockstep with everything
that we do.
Um,
and then when he goes about, um,
executing the plan on things, there's
certain things that he has to do that
that's just out of my wheelhouse.
And when it comes to execute, man, he
does a really good job of executing the
plan uh, of the vision that we have,
what we're trying to build. And that's
that's, um,
like I love every part of that. I do.
Even like on this trip we just went on,
I mean, we even got closer on this trip,
you know, and like
I'm looking forward to continuing to
doing that with him. I don't know if you
if you've ever asked you this, what what
about Darren that you want? Like like
what made you want to work with him?
I don't think you guys
>> super super well known when when you got
there.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So,
when I was going through the interview
process, this was
2022 or 2023. He was in Denver at that
time. And I was interviewing
for the Denver job. And
man, I can recall him sitting at the
end of the table.
Um,
and they asked me to do my my my first
speech Yeah. with the team.
And he was coordinating that.
And man, I just
I was at the top of my head. I just went
through a speech. And he was just like,
I love it.
>> [laughter]
>> I love it.
So, it was just seemed like it was
connection right then. And to me, it was
like, okay, well, he knows where I'm
coming from. He knows like we see it the
same way when it comes to the messaging
to the team and things like that. So,
and when we had a chance to sit and
talk, man, how he saw the team was
exactly how I saw it. AG, you spent a
week with him, basically. Say it again.
You just spent a week together flying
around the country.
>> Well, that was that's that's like that's
even But like I'm wondering like when
you guys are together for that long a
period of time, is it all ball talk? Do
you guys have any fun or
>> No, no, yeah,
yeah, we do stuff outside of it. I mean,
some when we were on the plane, his foot
hit my foot. I'm like, whoa.
>> [laughter]
>> So,
um,
so that was the argument we got into.
But, um, no, man, it's it's
we get away from football. Yes. You
know, and and we just talk about, you
know, life, kids, things like that,
which again, it makes the relationship
even better when you can
you can get away from, you know, things
that we know that's important and really
talk about other things that are
important, too. So, AG, you guys were so
good on special teams last year. I think
a lot of people were surprised to see
Nick Folk leave Yeah.
Are you concerned about the kicker
position right now? Listen, it that's
that's a position that you're always
concerned about because
because of the nature of how this game
is. I mean, a lot of these games
um
three points or less as far as so
Man, we really have to go through that
process and make sure that we find the
right guy for us. Yes, it's always hard
you know, losing a guy like that. Um but
here I I
I have the ultimate trust
in Banjo, in Coach O'Day to get the
right I mean, they are outstanding doing
their job and find the right guys for
us.
And they exhaust every option to make
sure we find the right guy. And I have
total trust in those guys of being able
to do it. You've been around this game a
long time and you know it's basically a
bottom line business. So, coming off
three wins
personally, like how much pressure do
you feel to show progress this year?
I might be different than than um
than a lot of coaches when I guess when
that question is asked because
you know, you hear the narrative.
I'm not you know, worried about my job
and
I'm not.
But I always put pressure on myself.
I've always done it as a player. So,
that's just
that's just who I am. You know, to me it
it's a pressure-packed business.
You know, as a corner it's pressure. As
a head coach it's pressure. So, it's
always pressure. That never goes away.
Now, when it comes to directing all that
I mean, I got it. But let's I'm going to
put pressure on myself
every game, every year. It doesn't
matter. I don't care if we won if we
went to the Super Bowl. It's always
pressure because now you have to try to
repeat that. So, I look at it that way.
You know, I don't look at it for
anything other than that of it's a
pressure-packed business and
listen, you got to win. That's what it's
about. You have used safeties a lot of
different ways over the years.
>> Say it again. You used safeties in a lot
of different ways over the years. Yeah.
In terms of Demaryius specifically Yeah.
>> is versatility going to be a plus and
then
how much can his influence help that
football team? I mean, it's it's it's
the reason why he's here, you know,
because of his influence.
Um
and I told him my definition of
leadership is really influence and
that's what he brings to the table. You
can go back to New Orleans when
Marcus Williams
um
the things that he's done then going to
Detroit with Kerb and BB, the things
that he's done man, he knows that and he
see that within the defense that we're
going to run and he's excited about
that. So, being able to use him at
nickel, being able to use him at safety,
being able to use him at dime. Those are
number of just a different like spots
you can put him in and watch him be
successful. And then it's hard to ID him
when you're able to do that as an
offense. Well, how do you feel about
your your wide receiver room? And well,
you have Garrett obviously and AD made
some catches and stuff last year, but
Yeah. And so, you hear Garrett all the
time and you should because he is a a a
true number one receiver. Um
but man, I I look forward to seeing what
AD is going to do, you know, going
through OTAs, going through the workout
program, um understanding exactly how we
go about doing things. I think it takes
that summer time to be able to bond with
your teammates and then getting to the
season. I know we just got him like
during the season, but to be able to see
him go through the whole process with
our guys um I really look forward to
that. And then like Isaiah, I mean,
obviously he's our punt returner, uh
kick returner also, but seeing him in
the slot and being able to do some
things. So, I'm I like the way our
receiver room is. I mean, obviously
you're always going to try to get
players um
that's going to help your team. So, um
but I look forward to seeing those guys
work together. Is there a player that
maybe
is flying under our radar, but that you
expect this year to take a nice leap
that might surprise some people this
I don't think he's flying under the
radar, but
I'm really looking forward to seeing
what Mason does this year. He's
talented. Yeah.
I I I
I think Mason's going to have a hell of
a year. I I really do. Um
cuz there are some things that we talked
about. That's something I talked to his
dad about, you know, if when we were in
Miami
uh working those guys out. Um
that you're going to see him like take
another step. So, I'm excited about that
player.
Um
I'm excited about our our tackles, our
blocking tackles.
Seeing those guys the way they're going
to operate.
Um obviously I'm excited about, you
know, all the guys we got in free
agency. So, you see how those guys but
if you if you were to ask me for one
person, like Mason, like that's the guy.
I think he's going to take another step.
With some of these trades that
Um
Well,
our conversation at the end of the year,
exit interviews
that was one of the realest
conversations that I've had yet for a
rookie, too. And
just like I tell you how I evaluate
myself
and he hear that. You know, when he
said, "Coach, just like you said you
were that, I'm evaluating myself, too.
And here are some things I know I have
to work on.
And here are some things you need to
hold me accountable for which he know I
will
so I can make sure I take the next step.
Um and again, that was a real
conversation and he was very adamant
about what the things that he want to
get better at. So,
again, another player with a chip on his
shoulder. You know, and I feel like um
he understands what he got to get better
at and how he's going to go about doing
it.
Another Muji question, but
>> Yep. I I feel like a lot of general
managers in the league they they
everyone publicizes draft picks, but
like it's like don't trade the pick.
Don't trade the pick. It's because of
the unknown instead of using them to
acquire players that are known. It seems
like Darren is a bit more open to the
idea of like the sixth, why don't we
Yeah, it's a lottery ticket in a way,
but why don't we go get the player that
we know exactly what he can be and that
can help our team now. Is that like a a
breath of fresh air? Cuz I don't I don't
feel like that's a a sentiment shared by
many around the Yeah, I I I I I I think
I understand the question and I think it
goes back to what um what we were saying
what I was saying before is
man, we love the player let's go get
him.
If we love the player, let's go get him.
And I think he does a really good job
number one of me and him communicating
on like how should we go about doing
this?
Um and I think he said this before, man,
his his his his phone he's going to
answer the phone, you know. Um which I
love that, you know, cuz you never know.
You never know.
Um man, the the the draft day is is I
love that day. I really do cuz you never
know what's going to happen. You hear
all these guys that's going to get
drafted in these certain spots and it's
never that.
>> [laughter]
>> You know, so to me that's the exciting
part of it and I love every part of it.
Hell, I was a part of it when I came
out. Shoot, I thought I was going to be
the sixth pick and I I ended up going
12, so
that's how it happened. Last one here,
guys.
All right, let me make it a good one
then. Oh.
>> [laughter]
>> Here comes the heavy hitter. You spoke
You're going to take his spot? Yeah,
yeah.
You spoke uh when you got hired, you
know, got unfinished business with the
Jets. And the Denver game and your
memories.
That's big picture. I know you're you're
you're focused on day-to-day what you're
doing. But how often do you reflect on
like I want to end this playoff drought.
I want to get this team to the
mountaintop. How like how often does
that come into your mind? Every day.
Every day.
Um
there's a couple things I think about
on a daily basis. Number one, I think
about the players every day.
And I think about like and I really
really think about this. Now, this is
not just coach speak of like how do I
utilize every player that we have on
this roster to help us be successful.
And then two, what are the things that I
have to do to make sure that man, we get
over that hump because I've been a part
of it and there's no better feeling in
the world than Okay, so we were down
trying for a number years
and then we finally get over that hump.
And now we're moving. But then again, so
now how do we keep that sustainable for
years to come?
Uh I want to leave a legacy. I do. You
know, when I'm when I'm gone
I mean, I'm I'm I'm
I'm looking at this team being a team
that that consistently puts themselves
in a in a place to win. And but every
day, you know, it's not
it's not a day, it's not an hour, it's
not a minute that I don't think about
that.
Um
and I look forward to trying to make
that happen. I really do.